Why will two portfolios employing the same underlying strategy run on the same as at
为何两个采用相同策略、针对相同股票池
universe during the same period yield
并在同一时间段运行的投资组合
a different portfolio if started at different points in time?
如果从不同的时间点开始 会产生不同的投资组合？
The reason is that transitions between different sets
因为在不同的投资组合权重集合之间过渡
of portfolio weights can be more or less costly.
成本可能更高或更低
Consider two portfolios trying to make the same transition to the same ideal portfolio.
假设有两个投资组合想要过渡到同一理想投资组合
A starting portfolio close to this portfolio might be directed here,
接近这个投资组合的起始投资组合可能朝着这个方向
but one starting from farther away might be directed elsewhere.
但是远离这个投资组合的起始投资组合可能会朝着其他方向
For example; say I start my strategy on January 1 and the signal says,
例如 假设策略从 1 月 1 日开始
go long Apple 10 percent.
交易信号是做多 10% 的 Apple 股票
So, I enter this 10 percent long position,
所以我做多 10%
then later on June 1,
之后在 6 月 1 日
the ideal position is to go short Apple 10 percent.
理想投资组合是做空 10% 的 Apple 股票
If I've imposed a turnover constraint or penalty in the problem,
如果我施加了周转率约束条件或惩罚项
the optimizer may not conclude that it's actually ideal to enter
优化器可能不认为
this 10 percent short position because
做空 10% 是理想的做法
it's too far away from the position I'm already in.
因为它与目前的头寸差别很大
However, if my way on Apple was previously zero,
但是 如果 Apple 的权重之前是 0
it may tell me that the best next step is to go 10 percent short on Apple.
那么下个最佳步骤也许是对 Apple 做空 10%
This could even happen for portfolio started at the same time but
从同一时间开始但是持有的资本量不同的
holding different amounts of capital if they have a liquidity constraint.
投资组合如果具有流动性约束条件 也可能会发生这种情况
A liquidity constraint means that we restrict our positions to be
流动性约束条件是指要求头寸低于
below some percent of each asset's daily trade volume.
每个资产的每日成交量的某个百分比
If two portfolios have different capital amounts than
如果两个投资组合的资本量不同
the smaller capital portfolio is less constrained by a liquidity constraint.
那么流动性约束条件对资本更小的投资组合限制更低
For example, if you have some small stock that trades one million dollars per day,
例如 假设有一些小盘股每天交易 100 万美元
and you have a small portfolio that wants to take
有一个小型投资组合想要
a 10 percent or 100k position in that stock,
对该股票建仓 10% 或 1 万
which is 10 percent of its volume, that would be okay.
等于成交量的 10% 这是可以的
But if you had a $100 million portfolio and the same Alpha vector,
但是如果是 1 亿美元的投资组合并且 Alpha 向量一样
then that portfolio would want to take a $10 million position in the stock,
那么该投资组合想要对该股票建仓 1000 万美元
which would be 10 times its daily volume,
相当于每日成交量的 10 倍
and so you'd only be able to take a very tiny position.
所以只能建很小的仓位
So, ultimately, due to these trading constraints,
这些交易约束条件会导致
the final portfolio weights of these portfolios would be very different.
最终的投资组合权重截然不同
In practice, you may see this effect if you run the same strategy for different clients.
在实践中 如果你针对不同的客户运行相同的策略 可能会遇到这种情况
Their portfolios may net different returns.
他们的投资组合可能会产生不同的收益率
This is the surprising but very common feature.
这很令人吃惊 但是也很常见
It also affects backtesting.
还会影响回溯测试
We've talked about backtesting only a little,
我们只是提了提回溯测试
but you'll recall that it involves rigorously simulating,
回溯测试涉及大量模拟工作
trading a portfolio by testing on historical data.
需要用历史数据测试投资组合
This type of simulation involves a lot of data and a lot of steps.
这种模拟会用到大量数据并包含很多步骤
You may want to speed it up by running parts of
你可能想要加快运行速度
the computation in parallel across many computers.
所以在很多计算机上同步运行某些计算步骤
However, this is difficult because each step of the computation where we calculate what
但是这很困难 因为在每个计算步骤
the portfolio would be at each point in
计算投资组合在每个时间点的状态
time is in practice dependent on the previous stage.
实际上取决于上一个阶段
We call this path dependency.
我们称之为路径依赖性
However, for portfolios of the same size over long periods of time,
但是 对于规模相同并且横跨很长时间（例如多年）的投资组合来说
like years, you would expect the paths of the portfolios to rejoin each other.
它们的路径会相互融合
People have attempted creative solutions to this difficulty.
人们尝试通过一些有创意的方法来解决这个问题
They may run simulations of 18-month windows of time that have
他们将模拟的时间窗口设为 18 个月
six months of overlap on different machines with the whole simulation spanning 10 years.
并且在不同的机器上有 6 个月的重叠期 整个模拟跨越 10 年
Then, they chop off three months on
然后截断每段模拟前后的三个月
either end of each simulation and stitch these together.
并将这些分段模拟连接到一起